Guide to the WXDU Records, 1963-2013 UA.09.13.0007
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
WXDU records
1963-2013
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
WXDU (Radio station: Durham, N.C.)
UA.09.13.0007
1.5 Linear Feet
WXDU, as a member of the Duke University Union, exists to inform, educate, and entertain both the students of Duke University and the surrounding community of Durham through quality progressive alternative radio programming. WXDU was founded in 1983 when former station WDUK-1600AM switched to a FM signal. Collection contains public records files, including correspondence and other materials related to FCC matters, program guides, clippings, a DJ handbook, and other materials. Materials range in date from 1977-2001.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The WXDU Records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1980, 1995-1996, 2001, 2017, and 2018.
Biographical/Historical note
WXDU, a non-profit student run radio station, was founded in 1983 when former station WDUK-1600AM switched to a FM signal. Whereas WDUK broadcasts were limited by the Federal Communications Commissions (FCC) to a range that barely covered the Duke University campus the new FM station WXDU could broadcast throughout the entire Durham community as well as the Duke University campus. The mission statement of WXDU proclaims that, as a member of the Duke University Union, [it] exists to inform, educate, and entertain both the students of Duke University and the surrounding community of Durham through quality progressive alternative radio programming.
Scope and Contents note
Collection contains materials pertaining to FCC matters including correspondence, playlists, Music Forums notebooks containing comments by DJs and staff on station happenings, DJ manuals, event flyers and publicity, employment reports, insurance policies, license applications and renewal, public service announcements, program guides, board member and staff lists, clippings, and other materials concerning the operation of the station.
Related Material
WDBS collection, 1949-1983,
University Archives. Duke University.
College radio stations; Radio broadcasting; Clippings (information artifacts); WXDU (Radio station: Durham, N.C.); WXDU -- Handbooks, manuals, etc. - DJ Handbook, 2000
- WDUK, 1977-1983, undated (Box 1)
- WXDU, Public File, 1995 (Box 1)
- FM Translator, public file, 1987-1995 (Box 1)
- License Renewal, public file, 1993; 1995 (Box 1)
- Public Service Announcements, public file, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
- Employment reports/Ownership reports, public file, 1988-1995 (Box 1)
- Insurance Information, public file, 1987 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous FCC Communications, public folder, 1983; 1991-1995 (Box 1)
- Program Guides, public file, 1986-1995 (Box 1)
- Records (taken from WXDU website), 2001 (Box 1)
- DJ Handbook, 2000 (Box 1)
- Reports on WXDU, 2003, undated (Box 1)
- Budget, 2004-2005 (Box 1)
- Show Reviews & Set Lists, 1990s (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1985-1997 (Box 1)
- Guidelines/instructing, 2007 (Box 1)
- Board Meeting Minutes, 2007 (Box 1)
- Playlists, 1995 (Box 1)
- WDUK Manuals, circa 1981 (Box 1)
- Bumper Sticker, undated (Box 1)
- Clippings, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
- Ideas!!, 1983-1996 (Box 1)
- AM to FM, 1981-1983 (Box 1)
- WXDU DJ Handbook, circa 1993 (Box 1)
- Flyers and Playlists, 1995 (Box 1)
- Playlists, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
- Station Manuals/Publications, 2005-2007 (Box 1)
- Promotional Flyers/Events Descriptions, 2007, undated (Box 1)
- Admin Records, 1983, 1994 (Box 1)
- Promotional Materials (Sample), circa 1990s (Box 1)
- Fundraising: Lists of People/Members, 1993-1996 (Box 1)
- FM License Apple, 1982 (Box 1)
- Map of Proposed Transmitter Tower, 1982 (Oversize-folder 1)
- Financial, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
- Financial, 1983-1984 (Box 1)
- Financial, 1994 (Box 1)
- PSAs (Public Service Announcements), 1994 (Box 1)
- Sample of Flow Sheets, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
- DJ Training Manuals, etc.., circa 1987-1993 (Box 1)
- Staff Attendance and Phone Lists, 1983-1997 (Box 1)
- WDUK 1600 AM Budget Reports/Constitution, circa 1982-1983 (Box 1)
- WXDU Board Positions, Correspondance, etc. Policies Procedures, 1990-1993, undated (Box 1)
- Duke U. Radio Board, Constitution, Minutes, Misc. Correspondance, 1987-1991 (Box 1)
- Handwritten Playlist Reports, circa 1996 (Box 1)
- CMJ Speciality Reporting Fax Sheets, circa 1996 (Box 1)
- Music Forum, 1994 (Box 1)
- Music Forum, 1995 (Box 1)
- Music Forum, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
- Music Forum, 1997 (Box 1)
- WXDU Records Library Catalog, circa 1990s (Box 1)
- Event Flyers, 1987-1997 (Box 1)
- Music Forum, undated (Box 2)
- Photographs, 1986, 1996-2003, undated; 5 folders (Box 2)
- Program Logs, 1960s (Box 2)
- Playlists, 1985 April 27 (Box 2)
- Playlists, circa 1990s (Box 2)
- Playlists and charts, 1985-1992 and undated (Box 2)
- Program Guides, 1986-2002 (Box 3)
- Posters and Flyers, 1987, 1991, 1997, undated (Box 3)
- Posters, 2011-2013, undated (Box 3)
- Posters and schematic, 1997 and undated (Oversize-folder 1)